# **IVAN RAHN**

# Full Stack Developer

Experienced in utilising JavaScript to optimise processes resulting in positive management decisions. I have initiated projects that automated and decreased business payment processing time by 75%. With a **"Build it better"** mind set, I'm enthusiastic about best practices and methodologies which aids in scalability and modularisation. Looking forward to help teams crush tech debts and build it right the first time.

++ I'm also a big PS4 FPS and RPG Gamer: especially Borderlands and Monster Hunter.



github.com/IvanRahn

in linkedin.com/in/ivanrahn

+61 412 126 599

#### Experience

#### Developer I Umbo

Nov 2018 - Present

Umbo provides early and consistent access to therapists for kids with special needs living in rural areas.

Developed a working prototype to aid Umbo in getting the right stakeholders onboard:

- Our Ruby on Rails solution enabled us to develop in a fast pace environment
- We built a complete user journey, from signup to matching clients with therapists and scheduling appointments.
- Our team of Nine strangers delivered a product in under 20-hours at the 'Random Hacks of Kindness, Australia' hackathon.
- ++ test it out at: http://umbo.herokuapp.com/

# Volunteer Developer | Youth Insearch

Nov 2018 - Present

An Independent Charitable Organisation, running positive life-changing youth intervention programs.

Front-end development, Style their 'always on' email messages with HTML and CSS.

# Office Manager | P.M.E.C. Pty Ltd

May 2015 - Present

P.M.E.C. provides professional education, migration and visa services in Australia, China and Thailand.

Initiated projects include:

- **Development with Javascript** to optimise business processes within the company's Google Suite, leading to a 2% decrease on business expenses.
- Co-developing new customer relationship management database, allowing better allocation of workload and increased customer retention.
- Implementing an MYOB Software Package, resulting in 30% decrease in bad debts and 75% decrease in Accounts Receivable and payable processing time.
- Facilitating managerial information flow, helping directors identify areas with higher potential and shift resources accordingly.

# Languages & Frameworks

Ruby on Rails

Rspec

**JavaScript** 

Express

React Node

MongoDB

HTML

CSS/SASS

Scripting for GSuite and Excel

-

English

Russian

## Tools & Tehniques

SMACSS methodology for CSS

VIM

\_

Version control

Pair Programming

Test Driven Development

Agile methodologies

Trello

\_

and a hint of Wireframing

### Bookkeeper I A.G.H. Education & Immigration Pty Ltd

Feb 2010 - Apr 2015

Australia Grace Home (AGH) offers friendly advice about migration and education in Australia.

Scripted and implemented automated invoice tracking and issuing, which resulted in:

- Recovery of over \$20,000 of unpaid debts
- Reducing receivables processing time by more than 50%.

## Manager I i-Ran Light & Sound Rentals

Feb 2010 - Apr 2015

A light/sound equipment and Dj hire company.

- Co-founded and managed a sound and lighting equipment rental business.
- In charge of staff acquisition, daily operations and finance.

#### Assistant Auditor | MCD-PKF

Nov 2007 - Jan 2009

A legal and business consultancy and appraisal company in St. Petersburg, Russia

- Co-developed automated audit processes through spreadsheet scripts.
- Trained new team members in international accounting standards.

#### Education

**Coder Academy** 

Aug 2018 - Present

Diploma of Information Technology, Web Development

- Gain more exposure to coding languages and best practices such as scalability and modularisation
- Utilise current frameworks and methodologies through various projects in JavaScript frameworks, Ruby on Rails, HTML/CSS
- · Practice agile rituals and ceremonies
- ++ find out more at www.github.com/lvanRahn

# **University of New South Wales**

Feb 2009 - Jul 2011

Bachelor of Commerce, Completed third years honors program

#### Saint Petersburg State University

Sep 2005 - Jan 2009

Bachelor in Accounting

#### Community involvement

#### Ruby On Rails Oceania

Speaker

Lightning talk on 'The wacky ways to flattening arrays' solving the exercism.com challenge.

Nov 2018

#### **Coder Academy**

Speaker

Lightning talk on 'A guide to Regex: Adventures of /PeterThePattern/'

Nov 2018

# Projects & Publications

#### Portflio Website

HTML/ CSS

\_

https://ivanrahn.github.io/portfolio/ Putting SMACSS methodology to

practice, modularising HTML components.

Oct 2018

#### **Casual Chef**

Ruby on Rails, Postgress QL Foundation framework.

\_\_\_

# https://www.github.com/IvanRahn/CasualMeals

Two way marketplace connecting casual chefs with customers based on their location.

Nov 2018

#### Umbo

Ruby on Rails, Javascript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, Heroku, AWS

\_

#### https://www.github.com/RHoK Australia/umbo

Our repo of Umbo's prototype to showcase matching Kids to the right Therapists.

Nov 2018